A Guide to the Papers of the President of the University of Virginia, Office Administrative Files, 1958
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of the President of the University of Virginia, Office Administrative Files 1958
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
RG-2/1/2.635-II
This collection consists of 11,400 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Access restrictions may apply to specific student records under the terms of the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (F.E.R.P.A.).
Acquisition Information
This collection was transferred to the library on 12 July 1963.
Scope and Content Information
These files constitute the major record series generated by the president of the University of Virginia. The records consist chiefly of correspondence, but also include reports, minutes, clippings, memoranda, and related papers concerning all areas of business of the president's office.
There are also architectural drawings of the West Grounds Site Plan, Engineering Building, and New Roads and three sheets of drawings for Proposed Changes in the North Approach to the Rotunda.
Contents List
- General Files
  - "A - Am" Miscellaneous 1958 (Box 1)
  - "An - Az" Miscellaneous 1958 (Box 1)
  - Admissions 1958 (Box 1)
  - Air Force 1958 (Box 1)
  - Airport 1958 (Box 1)
  - Alumni Associations 1958 (Box 1)
  - Alumni Fund 1958 (Box 1)
  - American Association of Land-Grant Colleges and Universities 1958 (Box 1)
  - American Association of University Professors 1958 (Box 2)
  - American Council on Education 1958 (Box 2)
  - American Field Service 1958 (Box 2)
  - Annual Reports 1958 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "A" 1958 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "B" 1958 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "C" 1958 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "D" 1958 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "E" 1958 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "F" 1958 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "G" 1958 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "H" 1958 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "I" (folder empty) 1958 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "J" 1958 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "K" 1958 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "L" 1958 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "M" 1958 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "N" 1958 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "O" 1958 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "P" 1958 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "Q" (folder empty) 1958 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "R" 1958 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "S" 1958 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "T" 1958 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "U" (folder empty) 1958 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "V" 1958 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "W" 1958 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "X - Y - Z" 1958 (Box 2)
  - Architecture 1958 (Box 3)
  - Army - General 1958 (Box 3)
  - Army - ROTC 1958 (Box 3)
  - Army - Judge Advocate General's School 1958 (Box 3)
  - Art 1958 (Box 3)
  - Art Commission 1958 (Box 3)
  - Association of American Colleges 1958 (Box 3)
  - Astronomy 1958 (Box 3)
  - Athletics 1958 (Box 3)
  - Athletics - NCAA 1958 (Box 3)
  - Atlantic Union 1958 (Box 3)
  - Attorney General 1958 (Box 3)
  - Auditor of Public Accounts 1958 (Box 3)
  - "Ba - Bl" Miscellaneous 1958 (Box 4)
  - "Bm - Bz" Miscellaneous 1958 (Box 4)
  - Bibilographical Society 1958 (Box 4)
  - Biology 1958 (Box 4)
  - Biology - Mountain Lake 1958 (Box 4)
  - Blandy Farm 1958 (Box 4)
  - Buildings and Grounds 1958 (Box 5)
  - Building Program - Architects and Engineers 1958 (Box 5)
  - Building Program - General 1958 (Box 5)
  - Building Program - Atomic Reactor 1958 (Box 5)
  - Building Program - Clinch Valley College: January - June 1958 (Box 5)
  - Building Program - Clinch Valley College: July - December 1958 (Box 5)
  - Building Program - Student Activities Building 1958 (Box 6)
  - Building Program - Commons 1958 (Box 6)
  - Building Program - Contracts (folder empty) 1958 (Box 6)
  - Building Program - Engineering House 1958 (Box 6)
  - Building Program - Field House 1958 (Box 6)
  - Building Program - Law School Building 1958 (Box 6)
  - Building Program - Life Science Building 1958 (Box 6)
  - Building Program - Medical Buildings 1958 (Box 6)
  - Building Program - Northern Virginia College 1958 (Box 6)
  - Building Program - Piedmont (folder empty) 1958 (Box 6)
  - Building Program - Power Plant and Heating Main 1958 (Box 6)
  - Bureau Population and Economic Research (folder empty) 1958 (Box 6)
  - Bursar 1958 (Box 7)
  - Business Administration, Graduate School of: January - June 1958 (Box 7)
  - Business Administration, Graduate School of: July - December 1958 (Box 7)
  - Byrd, Senator Harry F. 1958 (Box 7)
  - "Ca - Ck" Miscellaneous 1958 (Box 7)
  - "Cl - Cz" Miscellaneous 1958 (Box 7)
  - Carnegie Foundation 1958 (Box 8)
  - Catalogues (folder empty) 1958 (Box 8)
  - Cavalier Daily 1958 (Box 8)
  - Chemistry 1958 (Box 8)
  - Classics 1958 (Box 8)
  - Clippings 1958 (Box 8)
  - College of Arts and Sciences: January - June 1958 (Box 8)
  - College of Arts and Sciences: July - December 1958 (Box 8)
  - Commerce, McIntire Undergraduate School 1958 (Box 8)
  - Commission on Constitutional Government 1958 (Box 8)
  - Committee Suggestions 1958 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Accounts (folder empty) 1958 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Algernon Sydney Sullivan Award 1958 (Box 9)
  - Committee - All-University Advisory (folder empty) 1958 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Arboretum (O. E. White) (folder empty) 1958 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Art Museum (folder empty) 1958 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Athletic 1958 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Balch Estate 1958 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Betts 1958 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Biology Advisory 1958 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Blandy Farm Board (folder empty) 1958 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Board 1958 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Business Administration, Graduate School (folder empty) 1958 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Calendar (folder empty) 1958 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Cemetery (folder empty) 1958 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Chapel 1958 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Clinch Valley Advisory 1958 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Clinch Valley Building 1958 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Capacity of College (folder empty) 1958 (Box 9)
  - Committee - College Costs 1958 (Box 9)
  - Committee - College and Education 1958 (Box 9)
  - Committee - College, Graduate, and Education 1958 (Box 9)
  - Committee - College Reorganization 1958 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Commerce, McIntire Undergraduate School (folder empty) 1958 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Commerce, College and Business Administration (folder empty) 1958 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Computation Center 1958 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Contractual Relations (folder empty) 1958 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Counseling (see Student Counseling) 1958 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Dormitory Counselors' 1958 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Doshisha University Exchange Program (folder empty) 1958 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Education Advisory (folder empty) 1958 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Education, College and Graduate (folder empty) 1958 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Special Education 1958 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Emeritus Professors (folder empty) 1958 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Engineering Experiment Station Advisory (folder empty) 1958 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Extension (folder empty) 1958 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Extension Division, Head of 1958 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Extension Program in the State 1958 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Fellowship Awards (folder empty) 1958 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Fire Protection (folder empty) 1958 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Fraternity 1958 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Fulbright Award 1958 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Graduate (folder empty) 1958 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Hospital Architectural Advisory (folder empty) 1958 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Institute for Research in the Social Sciences Council (folder empty) 1958 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Page-Barbour and J. W. Richard (folder empty) 1958 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Special Lectures (folder empty) 1958 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Library (folder empty) 1958 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Life Science Building Plan (folder empty) 1958 (Box 9)
  - Committee - McConnell Award 1958 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Mary Washington College (folder empty) 1958 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Medical Board of the Hospital (folder empty) 1958 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Memorial - World War II 1958 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Miscellaneous 1958 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Mountain Lake Biological Station (folder empty) 1958 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Naval ROTC Selection 1958 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Non-Partisan for International Economic Growth 1958 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Nuclear Advisory 1958 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Nursing School Advisory (folder empty) 1958 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Old Dominion Foundation Grant 1958 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Patents 1958 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Planning 1958 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Power Plant (folder empty) 1958 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Presidents' Council 1958 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Processions 1958 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Public Occasions 1958 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Research 1958 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Research in the Social Sciences 1958 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Rhodes Scholarship (folder empty) 1958 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Richmond Area University Center Research Council (folder empty) 1958 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Rushton Seminars 1958 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Schedule and Classroom Assignments (folder empty) 1958 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Scholarships, Loans, and Employment (folder empty) 1958 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Science Education (folder empty) 1958 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Senate Membership (folder empty) 1958 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Snavely (folder empty) 1958 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Spectator 1958 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Student Activities Building, Decorating and Furnishing (folder empty) 1958 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Student Activities 1958 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Student Health 1958 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Student Union (folder empty) 1958 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Summer Session (folder empty) 1958 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Summer Session - Undergraduate Degrees (folder empty) 1958 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Summer Session - Graduate Degrees (folder empty) 1958 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Traffic Control (folder empty) 1958 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Tree 1958 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Undergraduates 1958 (Box 10)
  - Committee - University Center in Virginia 1958 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Virginia Quarterly Review1958 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Virginia Status of University Students 1958 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Visiting Scholars Program (see University Center in Virginia Commonwealth) (folder empty) 1958 (Box 10)
  - Conference on Atlantic Community 1958 (Box 10)
  - Council of Southern Universities 1958 (Box 10)
  - Comptroller 1958 (Box 10)
  - "D" Miscellaneous 1958 (Box 11)
  - Darden's File - Resignation, letters about 1958 (Box 11)
  - "E" Miscellaneous 1958 (Box 11)
  - Economics 1958 (Box 11)
  - Endowment Fund 1958 (Box 11)
  - Endowment Fund - Contingent Fund 1958 (Box 12)
  - Education 1958 (Box 12)
  - Engineering 1958 (Box 12)
  - English 1958 (Box 12)
  - Enrollment 1958 (Box 12)
  - Extension Division - January - June 1958 (Box 12)
  - Extension Division - July - December 1958 (Box 12)
  - Extension Division - Northern Virginia Branch 1958 (Box 12)
  - Extension Division - Southwest Virginia Branch 1958 (Box 12)
  - Extension Division - Richmond Branch 1958 (Box 13)
  - "F" Miscellaneous 1958 (Box 13)
  - Faculty 1958 (Box 13)
  - Fellowships and Scholarships - General 1958 (Box 13)
  - Fellowships and Scholarships - Ford 1958 (Box 13)
  - Fellowships and Scholarships - Fulbright 1958 (Box 13)
  - Fellowships and Scholarships - Rhodes 1958 (Box 13)
  - Finals 1958 (Box 13)
  - Food Service 1958 (Box 13)
  - Foreign Affairs 1958 (Box 13)
  - Forestry 1958 (Box 13)
  - Foundation Library Center 1958 (Box 13)
  - Founder's Day 1958 (Box 14)
  - Fraternities 1958 (Box 14)
  - Fund for Adult Education 1958 (Box 14)
  - "G" Miscellaneous 1958 (Box 14)
  - Geology 1958 (Box 14)
  - Germanic Languages and Russian 1958 (Box 14)
  - Gifts and Grants 1958 (Box 14)
  - Governor's Office 1958 (Box 14)
  - Governor's Office - Advices of Allotments 1958 (Box 15)
  - Graduate School of Arts and Sciences 1958 (Box 15)
  - Graduate School of Business Administration (folder empty) 1958 (Box 15)
  - "Ha - Hz" Miscellaneous 1958 (Box 15)
  - "Hm - Hz" Miscellaneous 1958 (Box 15)
  - Highway Department 1958 (Box 15)
  - Hildreth, W. S. 1958 (Box 15)
  - History 1958 (Box 15)
  - History - Madison Papers 1958 (Box 15)
  - Honor System 1958 (Box 15)
  - Hospital: January - June 1958 (Box 15)
  - Hospital: July - December 1958 (Box 15)
  - Hospital: Medical Board 1958 (Box 15)
  - Hospital: Statistical Reports of the Hospital 1958 (Box 16)
  - Housing 1958 (Box 16)
  - "I" Miscellaneous 1958 (Box 16)
  - International Association of Universities 1958 (Box 16)
  - Institute for International Education 1958 (Box 16)
  - Institute for Research in the Social Sciences 1958 (Box 16)
  - Insurance 1958 (Box 16)
  - Invitations - "A" 1958 (Box 16)
  - Invitations - "B" 1958 (Box 16)
  - Invitations - "C" 1958 (Box 16)
  - Invitations - "D" 1958 (Box 16)
  - Invitations - "E" 1958 (Box 16)
  - Invitations - "F" 1958 (Box 16)
  - Invitations - "G" (folder empty) 1958 (Box 16)
  - Invitations - "H" 1958 (Box 16)
  - Invitations - "I" 1958 (Box 16)
  - Invitations - "J" 1958 (Box 16)
  - Invitations - "K" 1958 (Box 16)
  - Invitations - "L" 1958 (Box 16)
  - Invitations - "M" 1958 (Box 16)
  - Invitations - "N" 1958 (Box 16)
  - Invitations - "O" 1958 (Box 16)
  - Invitations - "P" 1958 (Box 16)
  - Invitations - "Q" 1958 (Box 18)
  - Invitations - "R" 1958 (Box 18)
  - Invitations - "S" 1958 (Box 18)
  - Invitations - "T" 1958 (Box 18)
  - Invitations - "U" 1958 (Box 18)
  - Invitations - "V" 1958 (Box 18)
  - Invitations - "W" 1958 (Box 18)
  - Invitations - "X - Y - Z" 1958 (Box 18)
  - "J" Miscellaneous 1958 (Box 18)
  - Japan International Christian University 1958 (Box 18)
  - Jefferson, Thomas - Memorial Foundation 1958 (Box 19)
  - Jefferson, Thomas - Miscellaneous 1958 (Box 19)
  - "K" Miscellaneous 1958 (Box 19)
  - "L" Miscellaneous 1958 (Box 19)
  - Law School 1958 (Box 19)
    Contains memoranda from Dean F.D.G. Ribble to Colgate Darden on the legality of massive resistance and tuition grants.
  - Lectures - General 1958 (Box 19)
  - Lectures - Page-Barbour 1958 (Box 19)
  - Lectures - Richard (folder empty) 1958 (Box 19)
  - Legal Matters 1958 (Box 19)
  - Legislative Program 1958 (Box 20)
  - Library 1958 (Box 20)
  - Loan Funds 1958 (Box 20)
  - "Ma - Me" Miscellaneous 1958 (Box 20)
  - "Mi - Mz" Miscellaneous 1958 (Box 20)
  - Madison Hall 1958 (Box 20)
  - Mary Washington College - Dean Alvey 1958 (Box 20)
  - Mary Washington College - Dr. Simpson, Chancellor 1958 (Box 20)
  - Mary Washington College - Mr. Woodward 1958 (Box 21)
  - Mary Washington College - Miscellaneous 1958 (Box 21)
  - McConnell Award 1958 (Box 21)
  - Mathematics 1958 (Box 21)
  - Medicine 1958 (Box 21)
  - Monroe Commission 1958 (Box 21)
  - Music 1958 (Box 21)
  - "N" Miscellaneous 1958 (Box 21)
  - National Association of State Universities 1958 (Box 21)
  - National Conference of Christians and Jews 1958 (Box 21)
  - National Commission on Accrediting 1958 (Box 21)
  - National Science Foundation 1958 (Box 21)
  - Navy - General 1958 (Box 22)
  - Navy - ROTC 1958 (Box 22)
  - Newcomb Hall 1958 (Box 22)
  - Nursing School 1958 (Box 22)
  - "O" Miscellaneous 1958 (Box 22)
  - Oak Ridge 1958 (Box 22)
  - "Pa - Pe" Miscellaneous 1958 (Box 22)
  - "Pk - Pz" Miscellaneous 1958 (Box 22)
  - Personnel - State 1958 (Box 22)
  - Phi Beta Kappa 1958 (Box 22)
  - Philosophy 1958 (Box 22)
  - Photographs (folder empty) 1958 (Box 22)
  - Physics 1958 (Box 22)
  - Political Science 1958 (Box 22)
  - President's Council 1958 (Box 22)
  - Provost 1958 (Box 22)
  - Psychology 1958 (Box 22)
  - "Q" Miscellaneous 1958 (Box 23)
  - Questionnaires 1958 (Box 23)
  - "R" Miscellaneous 1958 (Box 23)
  - Radio 1958 (Box 23)
  - Raven Society 1958 (Box 23)
  - Recommendations 1958 (Box 23)
  - Regional Education 1958 (Box 23)
  - Registrar 1958 (Box 23)
  - Religion 1958 (Box 23)
  - Requisitions 1958 (Box 23)
  - Rockefeller Foundation 1958 (Box 23)
  - Romance Languages Department 1958 (Box 23)
  - Rural Social Economics 1958 (Box 23)
  - "Sa - Sl" Miscellaneous 1958 (Box 23)
  - "Sm - Sz" Miscellaneous 1958 (Box 24)
  - Segregation 1958 (Box 24)
  - Senate 1958 (Box 24)
  - Sigma Xi 1958 (Box 24)
  - Sociology 1958 (Box 24)
  - Southern Association of Colleges and Secondary Schools 1958 (Box 24)
  - Southern Association of Land-Grant Colleges 1958 (Box 24)
  - Southern Association of Science and Industry 1958 (Box 24)
  - Southern University Conference 1958 (Box 24)
  - Speech and Drama 1958 (Box 24)
  - Speeches and Articles 1958 (Box 24)
  - State Board of Education 1958 (Box 24)
  - State Council of Higher Education 1958 (Box 25)
  - State Department of Health 1958 (Box 25)
  - State Universities Association 1958 (Box 25)
  - Statistics 1958 (Box 25)
  - Student Affairs 1958 (Box 25)
  - Student Aid Office 1958 (Box 25)
  - Student Health Department 1958 (Box 26)
  - Summer Session 1958 (Box 26)
  - "T" Miscellaneous 1958 (Box 26)
  - Travel 1958 (Box 26)
  - Treasurer of Virginia 1958 (Box 26)
  - "U" Miscellaneous 1958 (Box 26)
  - United Nations 1958 (Box 26)
  - U. S. Department of Health, Welfare, and Education 1958 (Box 26)
  - U. S. Department of State 1958 (Box 26)
  - University Center in Virginia 1958 (Box 26)
  - University Houses 1958 (Box 27)
  - University News Service 1958 (Box 27)
  - University Press 1958 (Box 27)
  - "V" Miscellaneous 1958 (Box 27)
  - Virginia Academy of Science 1958 (Box 27)
  - Virginia Advisory Legislative Council 1958 (Box 27)
  - Virginia Education Association 1958 (Box 27)
  - Virginia Quarterly Review 1958 (Box 27)
  - Visitors: January - June 1958 (Box 27)
  - Visitors: July - December 1958 (Box 27)
  - Visitors - General, January - June 1958 (Box 27)
  - Visitors - General, July - December 1958 (Box 27)
  - Visitors - Berkeley, Mr. Norborne 1958 (Box 27)
  - Visitors - Bryan, Judge A. V. 1958 (Box 27)
  - Visitors - Coxe, Mr. Whitwell W. 1958 (Box 27)
  - Visitors - Emmett, Dr. J. M. 1958 (Box 27)
  - Visitors - Fenwick, Mr. Charles R. 1958 (Box 27)
  - Visitors - Gravatt, Mr. J. S. 1958 (Box 27)
  - Visitors - Gray, Mr. H. A. 1958 (Box 27)
  - Visitors - Greear, Mr. F. B. 1958 (Box 27)
  - Visitors - Hartfield, Mr. Joseph 1958 (Box 27)
  - Visitors - Jones, Mrs. B. T., Jr. 1958 (Box 27)
  - Visitors - Lanton, Mrs. Nathan 1958 (Box 27)
  - Visitors - McWane, Mr. Henry 1958 (Box 27)
  - Visitors - Martin, Dr. Walter B. 1958 (Box 27)
  - Visitors - Montague, Mr. Edgar Sclater 1958 (Box 27)
  - Visitors - Paschall, Mr. Davis Y. 1958 (Box 27)
  - Visitors - Pollock, Mr. Herbert 1958 (Box 27)
  - Visitors - Smith, Mrs. Herbert McK. 1958 (Box 27)
  - Visitors - Smith, Howard W. 1958 (Box 27)
  - Visitors - Talbott, Mr. Frank 1958 (Box 27)
  - Visitors - Wheeler, Ms. Lucille 1958 (Box 29)
  - Visitors - "Wa - Wh" Miscellaneous 1958 (Box 29)
  - Visitors - "Wi - Wz" Miscellaneous 1958 (Box 29)
  - Visitors - Washington Center of Metropolitan Studies 1958 (Box 29)
  - Visitors - Women, Dean of 1958 (Box 29)
  - Visitors - Wilson, Woodrow 1958 (Box 29)
  - Visitors - "X - Y - Z" Miscellaneous 1958 (Box 29)